Hello everyone, and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine,
and today we're going
to a very special place,
Marco, a place where
men and women alike, but usually women are
associated with it, and with these women
like to go, what is this
place we're going to?
That's right, today we
are going to a beauty spa.
All right, so let's check that out
in today's vocabulary preview.
Very capillary preview.
All right, so this
place, a beauty spa.
It's interesting because
it's not just a normal spa.
It's a particular spa where
you get treated for some things.
That's right, so a beauty spa is a place
where you go to feel good. So women and men
like to have their nails
and their faces and
their skin taking care
of, maybe their makeup
and hair as well, so
it's not just a place
where you maybe go
from massage, but you get
a lot of other services that make your
skin nice, make you look and feel good.
All right, so that's
where we're going today.
We're going to go to
a beauty spa, and we're
going to talk about
all the different things
that you can do there. So let's listen
to our dialogue for the very first time.
You want to get a facial with me today?
Dude, what are you talking about?
The girls do that.
Not at all. Guys also get
facials, manicures and pedicures.
There's nothing wrong with looking
after your skin and looking good.
True, so what should they
do to you at your beauty spa?
Well, first they exfoliate
my face, getting rid
of all the dead skin.
Then I get a face mask
with nutrients that keep
my skin healthy and young.
Afterwards, they apply some moisturizer
and you leave feeling like a million bucks.
That doesn't really sound like something I
would be interested in. In any case, I just
wash my face every night and
use sunscreen during the day.
Well, you should come with me one day.
I'm sure you'll love it.
Uh, no.
All right, we're back. So now let's
take a look at language takeaway.
Got a lot of great phrases and
words in language takeaway today.
The first one, though, is
from the very first line of dialogue.
You want to go get a facial with me today?
That's right. We are asking our friend if
he wants to go with us to go get a facial.
Now, what exactly does
it mean to get a facial?
All right, a facial here is a thing in this
case, a service that we would pay for.
Basically, a facial is just a skincare
treatment or a treatment for your face.
So maybe you'll get
some cream and cleansing
and, uh, you know,
in the advertisements,
you often see someone getting a
facial with like cucumbers on their eyes.
And so it's just a way to
make your skin feel really good.
Okay, particularly on your face.
Yes, your face and the verb here is to get.
So I'm going to get a facial
or I got a facial yesterday.
Okay, very good.
Now, um, we apart from
getting a facial, getting
a special treatment
on your face, you can also
get a manicure and a pedicure.
That's right. So
manicure pedicure, these
we're going to keep
together because they're
very similar, but they're
a little bit different.
Manny, manicure, Manny,
that means something
to do with the hands.
So manicure is actually
when you have your
finger nails kind of
cleaned and taken care of and then
they will apply some paint. So nail polish.
So basically having your
nails treated and then colored.
Okay, and then pedicure, I imagine,
is the same thing, but for your feet.
That's right. Petty
refers to feet.
So pedicure is the same
treatment, the same service,
but for your toes. And
in this case, you'd have
very, you know, nice
nail polish on your toes.
All right. Now, going
back to skin treatment,
because well manicure
and pedicure for your
fingernails and for
your hands and feet, we
are talking about getting
your face exfoliated
or he says, well, first
they exfoliate my face.
So exfoliate, you think X
means taking something away.
In this case, to exfoliate means to
take the dead skin away. And sometimes
this can be a little bit
painful because you
think at first you have some
dry skin, some dead skin.
They have to take it away.
They have to use something rough.
You can do it on your feet as well.
But when they exfoliate your face,
they use some kind of cleanser or some
kind of maybe sponge
to clear the dead skin.
And then afterwards you have the fresh new
skin and it's very smooth and nice looking.
Okay. So that's what it means to exfoliate
the skin. It can be on your face, your feet
pretty much
anywhere in your body.
And lastly, we also are
just using sunscreen during
the day to protect our
skin and to keep it healthy.
That's right. So sunscreen is a kind
of cream. Do you sunscreen Marco?
No. No, you don't have to. Well, I often
use sunscreen because I'm very, very pale.
And so when I go in
the sun, maybe at the
beach, it's very easy for me
to burn my skin to turn red.
And so sunscreen
helps me protect my skin.
So that's exactly what it does. sunscreen
is a specific type of lotion that you put
on your skin and it prevents you from
getting sunburns or from darkening your skin.
That's right. So those
are the words we have
relating to skincare and
some of these services
at the beauty spa, but
we've got some more
phrases for you. So
let's first listen to our
dialogue again and we'll
be back in a moment.
You want to get a
facial with me today?
Dude, what are you talking
about? Will the girls do that?
Not at all. Guys also get facials, manicures
and pedicures. There's nothing wrong
with looking after your
skin and looking good.
True. So what should they
do to you at your beauty spa?
Well, first they
exfoliate my face
getting rid of all the dead skin. Then I
get a face mask with nutrients that keep my
skin healthy and young.
Afterwards, they apply
some moisturizer and
you leave feeling like
a million bucks. That doesn't really sound
like something I would be interested in.
In any case, I just washed
my face every night and
you sunscreen during
the day. Well, you should
come with me one day.
I'm sure you'll love it.
Uh, no.
All right. So now it's time
for some fluency builder.
Let's check out
three key phrases.
Fluency builder. So we've got this first
phrase here, not at all. So one person says
only girls go to the beauty spa.
And what does the other person say?
Right. He says, no, not at all. Not at all.
So basically he's responding by saying,
no, that's not true. Now you could have
said no, but why do you say not at all?
You can say no, but
no is almost rude.
Uh, not at all is a way
to say, actually, in reality,
this is different.
So it's a, it's a more
polite way of disagreeing
with what the person just said.
Okay. So you can say, no, not at all.
I guess you can say both, right? Not
at all or together. No, not at all. No, not
at all. And you could say, um, women don't
like to watch football. And
you can say, oh, not at all.
You could say only men like to watch
football, right? And then if I disagree or you
say, actually, I can say,
no, not at all. Actually,
girls like to watch
football as well.
That's right. Okay. So
now continuing on with
the skincare topic,
we saw this interesting
verb to apply some moisturizer. So the verb
here is to apply something on your skin.
All right. So the verb to
apply means to put on,
okay, or to use. And
this is a verb we often use
with beauty care products
like apply the shampoo
to your head or apply
some fingernail polish
means that you're going
to, yeah, to put it on yourself.
Right. So when
we say, apply some
moisturizer is to use
moisturizer to put it on your skin.
Like I apply my makeup.
That means I put the makeup
on my skin. So in this case,
moisturizer is a great
cream that we use when our
skin is dry and we want
it to be more healthy.
We want it to be less
dry and we add this.
Okay. And lastly, after you
exfoliate, you apply moisturizer.
You do everything.
He says that you
leave the beauty salon
feeling like a million bucks.
All right. To feel like a million bucks,
this is a phrase that we often use to say,
you feel wonderful.
You feel great.
You feel really good. And so
this is the main reason to go
to the beauty spa
right, Marco. Right.
So you go there because you
want to feel like a million bucks.
So you feel very, very,
very good. Sometimes when
I buy a new outfit and I
try it on, I'm really excited.
I say, oh, I feel
like a million bucks.
So I guess the other
form of this word will
actually be, you look
like a million bucks.
Someone can look like
a million bucks. Exactly.
So I see my friend coming
from the beauty spa and I say,
wow, you look like a
million bucks. You look great.
All right. So let's listen to
our dialogue one last time.
There's review everything
and we'll be back in a bit.
You want to go get a
facial with me today?
Dude, what are you talking
about? Well, girls do that.
Not at all. Guys also get
facials, manicures and pedicures.
There's nothing wrong with looking
after your skin and looking good. True.
So what should they do
to you at your beauty spa?
Well, first they exfoliate
my face, getting rid
of all the dead skin.
Then I get a face mask with
nutrients that keep my
skin healthy and young.
Afterwards, they apply some
moisturizer and you leave
feeling like a million
bucks. That doesn't really
sound like something I
would be interested in.
In any case, I just washed my face every
night and used sunscreen during the day.
Well, you should come with me one day.
I'm sure you'll love it.
Uh, no.
All right. So facials, this sort of thing
is commonly mostly associated with women.
But as we saw in the
dialogue, more and more men
are actually taking care of
their skin and their appearance.
That's right. So while this might have been
traditionally a woman's event, going to
the spa, having a girl's day
at the spa, you're right, Marko.
A lot of men like to do this.
Just because you get a
manicure doesn't mean you
have to have pink
fingernails. You can actually
just have your nails
taken care of and cleaned
and cut and your
cuticles taken care of.
So it feels really nice.
That's right. Actually,
it's a common new
trend that we've even
heard in the news about.
And the term that men
are labeled with when
they take excessive care
of their skin and their
appearance, they say
they're metro-sexuals.
Metro sexual.
Right. Now, this is a
man who, like you say,
likes to dress nicely. It takes
care of his hair, has nice skin.
Someone who really
takes care of their body.
And it's different from being a homosexual,
for example, where maybe that's a
stereotype that we
have. Or we say, "Oh, well,
some people who are homosexual like to
dress very well and take care of their skin.
" Metro sexual people,
men are straight.
They're not gay. But they
still like to do these things
to go to the spa or to take
care of their appearances.
Right. So it's a very
interesting topic,
specifically nowadays
where this type of thing is
more and more common,
and yet still, in many places
and cultures, it's very
much taboo. Obviously,
being a manly
man-associated with that is, you
know, you don't really take
care of your appearance,
you know, you wake up and you still look
kind of messy and half asleep or, you know,
guy has scars and
beards and stuff.
So you don't really associate
it much. But it's very interesting
to see these types of
different cultural aspects.
So we would like to
know if in your culture,
your country, this is a common practice,
is it acceptable or is it very, very rare?
And if you go to the
beauty spa, whether
you're a man or a woman,
what's your favorite service?
Do you like the facials?
Do you like the pedicures?
Let us know. Our website is
www.EnglishPod.com. All right.
We'll see you guys there. Bye.